AMAH Akan Daniel

47, Lasisi Street, Orile-Iganmu, Lagos State.

·Telephone: (+234) 818 5037 181 · Email: danielamahtoday@gmail.com · LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-amah-2559a4159

· GitHub: https://github.com/AkanimohOD19A/

PROFESSIONAL ROFILE

I am a highly dedicated demographic analyst with working knowledge in the field and classroom of data collation, management and strategy. I have a track record of developing local and easy-to-deploy solutions in statistical software; designing digital art and websites; planning and managing IT-related projects. Based on my education and work experience, I have developed proficiency in design, data analytics and machine learning.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I desire to work/intern in a progressive environment where I can achieve excellent results and increase the company's profitability; and gain more experience within the role.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- SaaS
- MS Office Suite
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- Front-end Web Development
- Google My Business
- Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator & Canva

- SPSS
- R
- Python

STATA

- ODK
- Atlas TI
- Tableau
- Feature Engineering
- Machine Learning
- Research

- IT Support
- IT Management
- Admin Management
- Operations support
- Computer Hardware
- Presentation
- Problem-solving
- Requirement analysis and Documentation.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Computer Science Instructor

Surfworld Solutions, Odofado-Ilaje, Ondo State.

(10/2019 - 01/2020)

- Articulate and communicate basic Computer Use to secondary school students.
- Managed and optimized Computer Hardware, as well as records and preparing examinations within research laboratory.
- Scaled up basic competency in computer science in an underserved community.

Data Scientist and Operations (Intern)

Covens Lab, Akure, Ondo State

(04/2019 - 10/2020)

- Provided technical and non-technical support to facilitators during monthly data science classes.
- Curated daily content and peculiar offerings on social media: Twitter and Google My Business.
- Participated in the Machine Learning stream of Hotels.ng annual internship.
- Performed other duties as instructed.

Data Consultant (Student Research)

(06/2017 - 08/2017)

Dept. of Demography and Social Statistics, OAU, Ile-Ife, Osun State.

- Data compilation and analysis using software packages: SPSS and STATA.
- Provided technical and non-technical support in solving resource challenges.
- Trained on developing multiple template design: ODK and Epilnfo Framework.
- Produced and submitted a comprehensive report on Family Planning in the study area and received a report on my progress.
- Performed other duties and followed through on work commitments.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

B.Sc. (Hons.) Demography and Social Statistics [2:1]	2018	
Obafemi Awolowo University, Osun State (Nigeria)		
 Senior School Certificate Examination (SSCE) 	2012	
Nigerian Navy Secondary School, Abeokuta, Ogun State		

PROJECTS AND PORTFOLIO

- (Un)Published: Evaluation of Household Age Data in the Nigerian Demographic and Health Survey, 2013.
- (Rpubs) Automated reports and visualizations for NYSC opinion survey using RMD's.
- (OneDrive) Automating Dashboard & Slicers on daily National Covid-19 cases, Feb May 2020
- (<u>Websites</u>) Front-end website designs
- (Behance) Digital Designs in Adobe Illustrator.

PERSONAL DATA

Nationality:

Origin:

Uyo LGA, Akwa-Ibom

Sex:

Male

Languages:

English, Yoruba, Ibibio

Marital Status:

Single

Hobbies/Interests:

Studying, traveling and surfing the internet

REFEREES

Referees will be furnished on request.